

256 Phillip Street, Waterloo, Ontario, Canada

🛘 (+1) 416-823-8872 | 🗷 jackzyc1997@gmail.com | 🏕 www.jackzhuhack.space | 🖸 YuchenZhu | 🛅 YuchenZhu

Summary_

University of Waterloo 3A student working towards a Bachelors Degree in Computer Science with current GPA of 86. Quick learner of new technology with strong technical, business, and interpersonal skills. Passionate team player with hands-on experience in object-oriented programming and Java web development.

Work Experience _____

Desire2Learn Kitchener, Ontario

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER May. 2018 - August. 2019

- Designed and developed features for the Brightspace Data Platform (event-driven lambda architecture using AWS supporting 1000+ events per second)
- Implemented performance testing and improvements for real-time analytics dashboards.
- Debugging and testing the **token-based authentication** system to maintain web security.
- · Worked on mapping the java objects to relational database and SQL queries to fetch the data from the database.

Altairix Software Inc Toronto, Ontario

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER INTERN

Sep. 2018 - Dec. 2018

- · Work effectively with senior developers to manage complex design project for corporate clients.
- Design and implement Java batch job for data importing.
- Participate in Java web application developing/testing/debugging.
- Participate user interface development on Android studio.

Technical Skills

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGE, OS AND OTHER TECHNICAL SOFTWARES:

- Programming Language: C/C++, Java, JavaScript.
- Proficient with Xcode/Android Studio and IOS/Android application developing process.
- Experience with MySQL as backend Database and used JDBC for querying.
- Experience with developing interactive web application using **Node JS** a pure javascript application frame work.

Education

University of Waterloo, Ontario

CANDIDATE FOR HONOURS BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE, CO-OPERATIVE PROGRAM

Sep. 2016 - Present

- 1A, 1B Term, Excellent Academic Standing, Term Dean's Honours List
- Teaching Assistant for Math 135, 2019

Notable Projects _____

Course Recommender

SIMPLE ML BASED COURSE RECOMMENDING SYSTEM

June. 2019

- · Provide customized recommendations for students based on history enrollment data.
- Used Netflix movie recommending system as a reference.
- Used AWS SageMaker to build the machine learning workflow.
- Used Python3 for importing database and retrieving desired columns.

MineSweeper Game on IOS

UPLOADED ON GITHUB, READY TO UPLOAD TO APP STORE

Jan 2018

- A minesweeper game with sound effect and difficulty selection, playable on IOS devices.
- Designed and Implemented on IOS11 and Xcode9 using self-studied Swift programming language.
- Commended for Apple application development and self-learning skills.

Online Portfolio: www.jackzhuhack.space

Personal Website Oct. 2017

- Designed and coded in HTML5/CSS/Javascript.
- · Commended for user interface designing and web-site development skills.

SEPTEMBER 24, 2019 YUCHEN ZHU · RÉSUMÉ